Jacob Tarr



jtarr523@gmail.com



Mesa, AZ 85215

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Web developer, with an eye for design and 9+ years in the field, in search for employment at an agency or company who shares the same passion as I do in the web design field as well as making great websites for satisfied clients. My career is not just defined by my technical skills, but also by my ability to work with other team members, mentorship of junior developers, and ability to stay ahead of the curve in a rapidly evolving digital landscape.

SKILLS



EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Southleft, LLC-Remote, August 2022-July 2024

 Promoted to senior position and assumed more duties such as mentoring younger developers, collaborating more with team members on larger projects and communicating more closely with clients

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Southleft, LLC-Remote, August 2019-July 2022

- Responsible for the development of websites using modern CSS to handle intricate UI designs
- Build custom Wordpress website solutions for clients
- Work on a variety of platforms, including Gatbsy (React), Wordpress, Woocommerce, Craft CMS
- Apply Atomic Design architecture to websites, web applications, component libraries, and design systems
- Lead client development projects, ensuring seamless integration strategies for both new initiatives and existing codebases

FRONT END WEB / UI DEVELOPER, Akron

EYEMG Interactive Media Group-Akron, OH, November 2016-July 2019

- Responsible for PSD to HTML conversion
- Use modern CSS to handle intricate UI designs
- Use JavaScript (Angular.js, jQuery, Typeahead libraries) to power functionality
- Work with a custom (in-house developed) Perl CMS as a framework for most projects

- Code made-from-scratch Wordpress templates using the Sage starter template
- Collaborate with other team members using Git via Sourcetree

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER, Raleigh

Right Foot Forward Marketing & Design-Raleigh, NC, October 2016-December 2016

- Worked as a remote freelance developer
- Responsible for communicating with the team remotely on how to approach website functionality
- Code Adobe Experience Design mockups to custom Wordpress templates (using Understrap and Sage as a base)

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER, Akron

OuterBox Solutions-Akron, OH, March 2015-September 2016

- Use cutting-edge front end technologies and methodologies to transform mockups into clean and beautiful looking code on an ecommerce platform
- Implement front-end technologies into an ASP.Net (Razor) framework
- Develop for custom ecommerce solutions
- Update legacy websites from clients
- Work on an awesome team of developers to build websites clients can be happy about

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER (INTERN), Erie

Brain Gain, LLC-Erie, PA, April 2014-August 2014

- Develop front end side of a web application
- Responsible for presentation of website
- Designed the UI

EDUCATION

M.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE IN WEB DEVELOPMENT

Gannon University - Erie, PA, January 2012

B.A. IN JOURNALISM COMMUNICATIONS

Gannon University - Erie, PA, January 2005

WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO AND PROFILES

https://jacobtarrdev.com https://github.com/jacobtarr https://www.behance.net/jacobtarr

REFERENCES

References available upon request